Guide to the David Nichol Smith: Papers Related to Arden Shakespeare Series
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
David Nichol Smith papers
1904-1910
OSB MSS 10
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
1
(2 boxes)
The papers concern Smith's work on the Arden Shakespeare Series and include notes and collations for several plays, documents relating to editorial techniques and a small amount of professional correspondence.
Smith, David Nichol, 1875-1962
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Unspecified, please consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Notes and collations for King Lear, Measure for Measure, Henry V, and Two Gentlemen of Verona. Textual notes and documents related to editing Shakespeare. Correspondence 1904-10, to David Nichol Smith and Walter Raleigh.
Scholars -- Great Britain; Chapman, R. W. (Robert William), 1881-1960; Milford, Humphrey Sumner, Sir, 1877-1952; Raleigh, Walter, 1861-1922; Sampson, John, 1862-1931; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616 ( Criticism, Textual); Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616; Smith, David Nichol, 1875-1962
- Papers Relating to Arden Shakespeare Series
  - Notes and collations for King Lear; facsimile of 1608 Quarto 1 [Annotated] (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Notes and collations for Measure For Measure (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Notes and collations for The Tempest (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Notes and collations for Henry V (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Notes and collations for Two Gentlemen of Verona (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Textual notes on Shakespeare editions; MS register of Shakespeare publication dates and printers (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous documents relating to Shakespeare studies and editorial technique (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence
  - RW Chapman to David Nichol Smith (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Biographical/Historical note
    Chapman, Robert William, 1881-1960
    - ALS to David Nichol Smith. Comments on Henry V. Oxford, 1907 Apr 4
      General note
      2 p. 18 x 12 cm
    - Comments on Measure For Measure. Oxford, 1907 Apr 4
    - Has found term among Drayton's works, discusses numeration. Oxford, 1907 Aug 16
      6 p., 26 x 21 cm
    - Discusses numeration; textual issues. Oxford, 1907 Aug 22
      3 p., 26 x 21 cm
    - Encloses photographic enlargement of "Honours" and transcripts of 2 letters, H.H [art?] to ?, 1907 Aug 28 and 1907 Sep 2. Oxford, 1907 Sep 5
      1 p., 18 x 12 cm
    - Encloses cutting from Notes And Queries, 1907 Sep 11
    - . Oxford, 31 Aug., 1907
      2 p., 20 x 13 cm
    - Note on The Tempest. Oxford, 1908 Jan
      2 p., 18 x 12 cm
    - Encloses document on printing of Shakespeare Folio [Wanting]. Oxford [LS], 1909 Nov 18
      1 p. 17 x 21 cm
  - H.L. Milford to David Nichol Smith (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Milford, Sir Humphrey Sumner, 1877-
    - ALS to David Nichol Smith. Encloses sheets of King Lear from Oxford Folio [Wanting]. Oxford, 1905 May 30
      1 p. 14 x 12 cm
    - Notes on Shakespeare Text. Oxford, 1905 Jul 26
      3 p., 20 x 13 cm
    - Encloses proofs [Wanting]. Oxford, 1905 Sep 27
    - London, 1906 Nov 3
      1 p., 20 x 13 cm
    - Encloses 13 Harrap Vols. and Oxford, 1906 Nov 13
    - Shakespeare [Wanting]. London [LS], 1906 Nov 20
    - Encloses Bradley's replies to queries on Henry V [Wanting]. London
      1 p. 20 x 13 cm
    - Notes on Shakespeare Folio. London, 1906 Nov 27
      2 p. 20 x 13 cm
  - John Sampson to Walter Raleigh (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Sampson, John, 1862-1931
    - LS to Walter Raleigh. Notes on Shakespeare edition. Liverpool, 1904 Nov 9
      4 p., 18 x 12 cm
    - Encloses specimen page [Wanting]; notes on Shakespeare edition. Liverpool, 1904 Dec 21
    - Glad to hear his approval; Notes on Shakespeare text. N.P., 1904 Dec 26
      6 p., 18 x 12 cm
    - Notes on Shakespeare edition. Liverpool, 1904 Dec 28
      4 p., 20 x 13 cm
  - Correspondence, Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Cannan, Charles
      - Letter to David Nichol Smith. Encloses specimens of King Lear text [Wanting]. Oxford, 1905 Aug 23
      - ALS to David Nichol Smith. Textual notes on Shakespeare. Oxford, 1907 Jul 17; 5 p., 26 x 21 cm
      - LS to David Nichol Smith. Notes on Shakespeare edition. Oxford, 1907 Aug 7
        4 p., 26 x 21 cm
    - Fitzgerald, James D.
      - ALS to David Nichol Smith. Encloses "The First Quarto of Hamlet a Literary Fraud", 1910. Glasgow, 1910 Nov 1
        1 p., 12 x 18 cm
    - Judy, C.K.
      - ALS to David Nichol Smith. Remarks on editions of Titus Andronicus. London, n.y. Jul 25
        1 p., 18 x 26 cm
    - Malcolm, I.S.
      - LS to David Nichol Smith. Encloses advertisments for Caxton edition of Shakespeare's works. London, 1910 May 28
        2 p. 26 x 21 cm
    - Merz, Teresa
      - ALS to David Nichol Smith. Encloses MS copy of newspaper cutting. Newcastle upon Tyne, 1908 Nov 1
    - Simpson, Percy 1865-1962
      - ALS to ?. Encloses note on Gifford's Ben Jonson, v. VII. N/P, No year, Oct 9
        1 p., 10 x 12 cm
    - Smith, David Nichol, 1875-1962
      - ALS to Charles Cannan. Notes on Shakespeare Folios and Quartos. Newcastle upon Tyne, 1907 Aug 15
  - Several folders of miscellaneous correspondence, galleys and notes relating to D. N. Smith (Box 2)